Tejas Nikumbh

+91 7506081238 tejnikumbh@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a Full Stack Developer with experience in Python and Django as a backend Technology and iOS + Android as Front End Technologies. I have also done Javascript in the past. I love building new things and pick up new technology pretty fast.

EDUCATION

- Dual Degree in Electrical Engineering (Bachelors + Masters) IIT Bombay
- Masters GPA of 9.0 on 10.0 with thesis in Machine Learning & Computing

EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur in Residence, Entrepreneur First, London Mar 2016 - Jul 2016 Entrepreneur First is Europe's leading accelerator for Deep Tech Startups. I was a member of the cohort EF6 which had an acceptance rate of less than 3%.

- * I worked on an Immersive VR app for concerts integrating Google VR SDK
- * I worked on a context aware SDK that predicts user context from sensor data

Software Developer, Housing.com, Mumbai, India Jun 2015 - Mar 2016

- * I worked on integrating the Uber API into Housing's Native iOS app
- * I worked on the app facing layer of the Analytics SDK for the Native iOS app
- * I built a universal App Rating Flow mechanism for Housing's Native iOS app

Software Developer, Stanford, Columbia & Caltech, Remote Jul 2013 - Sep 2013

- * I had to design, build and deploy the gameplay logic for an Economics game
- * I collaborated with a team of faculty & researchers from Stanford, Columbia, Caltech & Harvard as a part of this project to architect the game and develop it in Javascript

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Design and Implementation of Efficient techniques for ALLSAT - Masters Thesis $[9.0 \mid 10.0]$, IIT Bombay — Jul 2014 - Jul 2015

Master's Thesis implementing novel techniques for ALLSAT using Minimal Blocking Clauses. ML Classification and Ensemble techniques to build highly accurate purpose driven SAT Classifiers with accuracies as high as >98% [Python + Matlab]

Limited Precision Neural Nets, IIT Bombay - Supervised Research Exposition [Perfect Score - $10.0 \mid 10.0$] Aug 2013 - Dec 2013

Analyzed change in accuracy of fully connected Neural Networks for classification of handwritten digits by varying Bit Precision. Observed a change of 4.16% [96.00% for 32 bits to 91.84% for 4 bits], suggestive of possible implementation in Embedded Systems [Python]

ACHIEVEMENTS

AngelHack Mumbai 2015 - API Prize from HP for Android App 'Vida Loca'

Built an 'Auto video tagging and search' application packaged as a Lifestyle App. Used HP's IDOL on demand API and won for it's best use at AngelHack Mumbai

Redefine 2.0 - Housing.com Hackathon 2015 - Winner 1st place for iOS App 'Joy' Joy was an on demand donations app facilitating a smooth donation process for donors as well as NGO's. We won the company wide Hackathon for this app.

HOBBY PROJECTS

Imagine - Platform with a Python+Django backend aimed at creating a new form of delivery for short stories. Each story has descriptive scenes attached to paragraphs that enable the user to 'see' the story alongside reading it. Native iOS App in beta. Android coming soon. Used Django Rest Framework for API creation.

Random Writer - Algorithm that auto generates non sensical stories using supplied corpus of text as training data. Used Markov Models of varying order to generate the stories in C++

Evil Hangman - Console based game (a twist on the regular hangman) that cheats behind the scenes to minimize player's chances of winning. The program was built in C++ and involved a Probabilistic Model for computing chances of winning

Cluster - Mini Social Network (Native iOS App) for exchange of business information. Also saved meta data about where the connection was formed. Backend was built in Parse.

Mathblitz - Native Android App with no backend for making Mental Math fun. Embedded gamification and Ad Revenue Generation. Average Rating >4.9 across >150 downloads on the Play Store

Trader Geek -Native Android App with no backend for Interview Test Prep for Junior Trader positions at trading firms. Got a humongous response with > 500 downloads and Average Rating of > 4.5 on the Play Store

Gear Alert -Native iOS App with Flask + Python backend involving location (on a map), and retrieval of missing Fish Gear in the Oceans. Primarily targeted at solving the problem of gear vessel collision. Built at Fishackathon London 2016

Vida Loca -Native Android App involving use of HP's Machine Learning APIs . This app auto tagged and generated appropriate summaries for videos taken through an Android Phone. We won Angel Hack Mumbai's best use of HP API prize for this

Joy -Native iOS App with PHP + Laravel Backend for facilitating of donations involving donors and NGOs. We won the company wide Hackathon at Housing for this app in 2015.